Pottabattini Santosh Kumar

Senior Software Engineer

+91-8309012899 | santosh.pk@hotmail.com | Hyderabad, Telangana, India Linked IN | Website

SUMMARY

Im a Senior Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience in the industry, and am specialized in React Native mobile app development. I have developed solid back-end development capabilities in addition to my great frontend programming abilities. I constantly deliver top-notch code while considering improving user experience top of mind. My focus is on driving innovation and achieving exceptional results in software development projects.

SKILLS

Languages and Frameworks:

- React-native
- **AWS**
- **Javascript**
- Typescript
- Redux & Redux toolkit
- Node is

- Python
- Git
- React js
- **Firebase**
- Mongo db

Tools:

- Android-Studio
- X code
- VS code

Postman

Methodologies:

Agile/Scrum

WORK EXPERIENCE

Hexagon Capability Center

Aug 2021 - Present

Senior Software Engineer

Hyderabad, Telangana

- Prioritized and Resolved high-priority bugs under tight deadlines, ensuring 100% up-time during critical releases and improving user retention
- Performed unit testing using Jest and React Testing Library, achieving 90% test coverage and enhancing release quality by identifying and resolving issues pre-launch.
- Led a React Native upgrade project, resolving compatibility issues and optimizing code base, reducing app load time by 30% and enhancing cross-device performance.
- Developed new app features, including Android auto, Apple car-play, Siri Voice commands, while maintaining app stability, boosting performance metrics by 20% without regression issues.
- Led a full rewrite of a legacy application into React Native within a six-month timeline, successfully deploying it to production with improved stability and performance for clients.

Bitzop Technologies Pvt Ltd

Apr 2019 - Aug 2021

Software Engineer

Hyderabad, Telangana

- Designed and implemented user interfaces from client-provided designs, enhancing visual consistency.
- Created custom UI components (e.g., Filter drop-downs, Dynamic forms), increasing app interaction time by 15% through streamlined component reuse and functionality.
- Utilized React Hooks to transform class components, reducing code base complexity by 25% and improving app performance, decreasing load times by an average of 1 sec.
- Integrated back-end services using REST API's, enhancing data flow between front-end and back-end, reducing data transfer time by 20%.
- Resolved critical bugs and optimized app functionality, ensuring timely project completion and maintaining a high user satisfaction rate above 90%.

 Collaborated in Agile team scrums, contributing to design sprints, reducing iteration cycles by 10% through effective cross- functional team collaboration.

EDUCATION

Mahaveer Institute of Science And Technology

2014 - 2018

Computer Science Engineering

Hyderabad, Telangana

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

HxGN OnCall Mobile App

Aug 2021 - current

Hexagon Capability Center

• Developed event management functionality, achieving a 90% satisfaction rating. Collaborated to resolve bugs, improving app performance by 20%.

Intergraph Mobile Responder RN

May 2023 - current

Hexagon Capability Center

• Led a full rewrite of a legacy application into React Native, replicating all original features and UI to preserve the familiar user experience while enhancing stability and performance. Completed the project within six months, ensuring users could transition seamlessly to the new technology without disruption.

Cogensia's Customer Management Platform (CMP)

Sep 2019 - July 2020

Bitzop Technologies Pvt Ltd

• Led UI design using React, increasing usability by 30%; engineered data integration for targeted marketing, boosting response rate by 20%.

InXite Health System App

July 2020 - Aug 2021

Bitzop Technologies Pvt Ltd

• Developed a health tracking app focused on physical, social, and mental factors, achieving a 40% engagement rate.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Pat on the Back: Earned 3 awards for high-quality work and problem-solving on key projects.
- Star Award: Recognized as part of the team for successful project delivery and client satisfaction at Hexagon Capability Center India.